<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Ugly Bugs</string>
    <string name="dialogo_imagenes_titulo">IMAGES</string>
    <string name="dialogo_titulo">UGLY BUGS</string>
    <string name="frag_acerca_de_text">ABOUT</string>
    <string name="frag_enlaces_text">LINKS</string>
    <string name="frag_idioma_text">LANGUAGE</string>
    <string name="frag_imag_text">IMAGES</string>
    <string name="frag_info_text">INFO</string>
    <string name="nombre_app">UGLY</string>
    <string name="nombre_app1">BUGS</string>
    <string name="frag_imag_mantis">Praying mantis</string>
    <string name="mantis">Praying mantis (Mantis religiosa religiosa)</string>
    <string name="mantis2">Praying mantis (Mantis religiosa religiosa)</string>
    <string name="mantis3">Praying mantis (Mantis religiosa religiosa)</string>
    <string name="mantis4">Praying mantis (Mantis religiosa religiosa)</string>
    <string name="mantis5">Praying mantis (Mantis religiosa religiosa)</string>
    <string name="mantis6">Praying mantis (Mantis religiosa religiosa)</string>
    <string name="mantis7">Praying mantis (Mantis religiosa religiosa)</string>

    <string name="salir">Touch again to exit</string>
    <string name="dialogo_salir">Exit</string>
    <string name="frag_imag_Hormigas">Ants</string>
    <string name="frag_imag_colore">Coloured images</string>
    <string name="frag_imag_escarabajos">Beetles </string>
    <string name="frag_imag_gorgojos">Weevils</string>
    <string name="frag_imag_grillos">Crickets</string>
    <string name="frag_imag_moscas">Fly</string>
    <string name="frag_imag_polillas">Moths</string>
    <string name="frag_imag_saltamontes">Grasshopper</string>
    <string name="frag_imag_tabanos">Horsefly</string>
    <string name="frag_imagenes">Assorted images</string>
    <string name="frag_imagenes1">Assorted images</string>
    <string name="frag_imagenes_info">Images</string>
    <string name="frag_mosca">Common fruit fly</string>
    <string name="frag_mosquito">Eye of a mosquito</string>
    <string name="frag_piojo">Flea</string>
    <string name="frag_pulga">Cat flea</string>
    <string name="frag_tecnica">Techniques</string>
    <string name="frag_teoria">Theory</string>

    <string name="avispa">Tarantula hawk (Pepsini)</string>
    <string name="avispa2">Wasp (Hymenoptera)</string>
    <string name="avispa3">Carpenter bee (Xylocopa)</string>
    <string name="avispa4">Digger wasps (Sphex)</string>
    <string name="avispa5">Parasitoid wasp (Braconidae)</string>
    <string name="avispa6">Parasitoid wasp (Ichneumonidae</string>
    <string name="avispa7">Parasitoid wasp (Ichneumonidae</string>
    <string name="avispa8">Parasitoid wasp. Netelia producta (Tryphoninae)</string>
    <string name="no_network_connection_toast">No network connection found</string>
    <string name="escarabajo">Shining flower beetles (Phalacridae)</string>
    <string name="escarabajo2">Ladybug (Coccinellidae)</string>
    <string name="escarabajo3">Ladybug, detail of a leg. (Coccinellidae</string>
    <string name="escarabajo4">Ground beetle (Carabidae)</string>
    <string name="escarabajo5">Dung beetle (Scarabaeus viettei)</string>
    <string name="escarabajo6">Eastern eyed click beetle (Alaus oculatus)</string>
    <string name="escarabajo7">Eastern Hercules beetle (Dynastes tityus)</string>
    <string name="escarabajo8">Longhorn beetle (Cerambycidae)</string>
    <string name="escarabajo9">Cockroaches (Blattodea)</string>
    <string name="escarabajo10">Herculer beetles (Dynastinae)</string>
    <string name="CheckInternet">Network error!</string>
    <string name="CheckInternet1">You will not see any pictures or videos</string>
    <string name="dialogo_ayuda_texto">\nClick the image to see the insect\'s name. Then, click the Wikipedia button to find out all about it.  \n\nUse the arrow button to download a zip file with all the content in the Images section (it\'s stored in the Downloads section of your phone). \n\nTo unzip it, you can use the Play Store RAR app: \"https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rarlab.rar\". \n\nAll pictures in this section are taken from \"Ugly Bugs\" (Go to the Links section to visit the website). The specific species isn\'t stated, but since all specimens are from Oklahoma it\'s safe to assume that it\'s a Praying Mantis, which is the most common (if not the only one) in the US.</string>
    <string name="dialogo_ayuda_texto_modelo">\nClick the image to see the insect\'s name. Then, click the Wikipedia button to find out all about it.  \n\nUse the arrow button to download a zip file with all the content in the Images section (it\'s stored in the Downloads section of your phone). \n\nTo unzip it, you can use the Play Store RAR app: \"https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rarlab.rar\".</string>
    <string name="dialogo_ayuda_titulo">HELP</string>
    <string name="dialogo_info">\nThis App showcases a great variety of different insects, using highly detailed images made by a scanning electron microscope (SEM). They can be found in the Images section, sorted by taxonomic order, and there\'s also a selection of colour pics. \n\nThe Information section contains data on how these images are made as well as technical information about the instruments used. \n\nThe Links section includes a selection of websites with information and pictures (which are the source for some of the App\'s pictures). \n\nIn the Videos section you\'ll find two very cool 3D colour animation videos and an additional selection of images. \n\nClick the App icon to see this text again. You can also click the App icon on other screens to see further information and help.\n\n</string>
    <string name="dialogo_imagenes_texto">\nThis section displays images of different insects (mantis, wasps and more) made with a Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM). You can enlarge the pics and rotate the screen to enhance your viewing experience. \n\nPlease note that when collecting the images it has not always been possible to accurately determine the name of the species. This App is not made by an entomologist (it\'s mainly an image app), so if you find any errors, do let me know! You can find contact details in the About section.\n\n</string>
    <string name="enlaces">Visit these links to find out more about scanning electron microscopes (SEM) and see some cool images! http://www.uglybug.org/</string>
    <string name="frag_imag_avispas">Wasps, Bees</string>
    <string name="gorgojo">Weevil (Curculio nucum)</string>
    <string name="gorgojo2">Weevil (Curculio nucum)</string>
    <string name="gorgojo3">Weevil (Curculio nucum)</string>
    <string name="gorgojo4">Rice weevil (Sitophilus oryzae)</string>
    <string name="gorgojo5">Bamboo Shoot Weevil (Dryophthorinae)</string>
    <string name="gorgojo6">Asiatic weevil (Orthotemnus longitarsus)</string>
    <string name="mensajePager">Touch the image to know its name, go to Wikipedia or download the content.</string>
    <string name="tabano">Horse-fly (Tabanidae)</string>
    <string name="tabano2">Horse-fly (Tabanidae)</string>
    <string name="tabano3">Horse-fly (Tabanidae)</string>
    <string name="tabano4">Horse-fly (Tabanidae)</string>
    <string name="tabano5">Dark giant horsefly (Tabanus sudeticus)</string>
    <string name="grillo">Camel cricket (Rhaphidophoridae)</string>
    <string name="grillo2">Northern  Mole cricket (Gryllotalpidae)</string>
    <string name="grillo3">Mole cricket (Gryllotalpidae)</string>
    <string name="grillo4">Mole cricket (Gryllotalpidae)</string>
    <string name="grillo5">Mole cricket (Gryllotalpidae)</string>
    <string name="grillo6">Mole cricket (Gryllotalpidae)</string>
    <string name="grillo7">Mole cricket (Gryllotalpidae)</string>
    <string name="grillo8">Mole cricket (Gryllotalpidae)</string>
    <string name="grillo9">Northern Mole cricket (Neocurtilla hexadactyla)</string>
    <string name="hormiga">Panda ant (Mutillidae)</string>
    <string name="hormiga2">Antlion (Myrmeleontidae)</string>
    <string name="hormiga4">Antlion (Myrmeleontidae)</string>
    <string name="hormiga5">Antlion (Myrmeleontidae)</string>
    <string name="hormiga3">Antlion (Myrmeleontidae)</string>
    <string name="hormiga6">Fire ant (Solenopsis invicta)</string>
    <string name="mosca">Robber fly (Asilidae)</string>
    <string name="mosca2">Robber fly (Asilidae)</string>
    <string name="mosca3">Robber fly (Asilidae)</string>
    <string name="mosca4">Fan-bristled robberfly (Dysmachus trigonus)</string>
    <string name="mosca5">Fan-bristled robberfly (Dysmachus trigonus)</string>
    <string name="mosca6">Bee fly (Bombylius)</string>
    <string name="mosca7">House fly (Musca domestica</string>
    <string name="mosca8">Mydas fly (Mydidae</string>
    <string name="polilla">Hawk moth (Manduca quinquemaculata)</string>
    <string name="polilla2">Common clothes moth (Tineola bisselliella)</string>
    <string name="polilla3">Privet hawk moth (Sphinx ligustri)</string>
    <string name="polilla4">Privet hawk moth (Sphinx ligustri)</string>
    <string name="polilla5">Privet hawk moth (Sphinx ligustri)</string>
    <string name="polilla6">Privet hawk moth (Sphinx ligustri)</string>
    <string name="polilla7">Drain fly (Clogmia albipunctata)</string>
    <string name="saltamontes">Grasshopper (Acrididae)</string>
    <string name="saltamontes2">Grasshopper (Acrididae)</string>
    <string name="saltamontes3">Grasshopper (Acrididae)</string>
    <string name="saltamontes4">Grasshopper (Acrididae)</string>
    <string name="saltamontes5">Grasshopper (Acrididae)</string>
    <string name="saltamontes6">Grasshopper (Acrididae)</string>
    <string name="saltamontes7">Grasshopper (Caelifera)</string>
    <string name="teoria1">\n<b>DESCRIPTION</b>\n\nA scanning electron microscope (SEM) is a type of electron microscope that produces images of a sample by scanning it with a focused beam of electrons. The electrons interact with atoms in the sample, producing various signals that contain information about the sample\'s surface topography and composition. The electron beam is generally scanned in a raster scan pattern, and the beam\'s position is combined with the detected signal to produce an image. SEM can achieve resolution better than 1 nanometer. Specimens can be observed in high vacuum, in low vacuum, in wet conditions (in environmental SEM), and at a wide range of cryogenic or elevated temperatures.\n\nThe most common SEM mode is detection of secondary electrons emitted by atoms excited by the electron beam. The number of secondary electrons that can be detected depends, among other things, on specimen topography. By scanning the sample and collecting the secondary electrons that are emitted using a special detector, an image displaying the topography of the surface is created.\n</string>
    <string name="teoria2">\n<b>PRINCIPLES AND CAPACITIES</b>\n\nThe types of signals produced by an SEM include secondary electrons (SE), reflected or back-scattered electrons (BSE), photons of characteristic X-rays and light (cathodoluminescence) (CL), absorbed current (specimen current) and transmitted electrons. Secondary electron detectors are standard equipment in all SEMs, but it is rare that a single machine would have detectors for all other possible signals.\n\nThe signals result from interactions of the electron beam with atoms at various depths within the sample. In the most common or standard detection mode, secondary electron imaging or SEI, the secondary electrons are emitted from very close to the specimen surface. Consequently, SEM can produce very high-resolution images of a sample surface, revealing details less than 1 nm in size. Back-scattered electrons (BSE) are beam electrons that are reflected from the sample by elastic scattering. They emerge from deeper locations within the specimen and consequently the resolution of BSE images is generally poorer than SE images. However, BSE are often used in analytical SEM along with the spectra made from the characteristic X-rays, because the intensity of the BSE signal is strongly related to the atomic number (Z) of the specimen. BSE images can provide information about the distribution of different elements in the sample. For the same reason, BSE imaging can image colloidal gold immuno-labels of 5 or 10 nm diameter, which would otherwise be difficult or impossible to detect in secondary electron images in biological specimens. Characteristic X-rays are emitted when the electron beam removes an inner shell electron from the sample, causing a higher-energy electron to fill the shell and release energy. These characteristic X-rays are used to identify the composition and measure the abundance of elements in the sample.\n\nDue to the very narrow electron beam, SEM micrographs have a large depth of field yielding a characteristic three-dimensional appearance useful for understanding the surface structure of a sample. This is exemplified by the micrograph of pollen shown above. A wide range of magnifications is possible, from about 10 times (about equivalent to that of a powerful hand-lens) to more than 500,000 times, about 250 times the magnification limit of the best light microscopes.\n</string>

    <string name="teoria3">\n<b>SCANNING PROCESS AND IMAGE FORMATION</b>\n\nIn a typical SEM, an electron beam is thermionically emitted from an electron gun fitted with a tungsten filament cathode. Tungsten is normally used in thermionic electron guns because it has the highest melting point and lowest vapor pressure of all metals, thereby allowing it to be electrically heated for electron emission, and because of its low cost. Other types of electron emitters include lanthanum hexaboride (LaB6) cathodes, which can be used in a standard tungsten filament SEM if the vacuum system is upgraded or field emission guns (FEG), which may be of the cold-cathode type using tungsten single crystal emitters or the thermally assisted Schottky type, that use emitters of zirconium oxide.\n\nThe electron beam, which typically has an energy ranging from 0.2 keV to 40 keV, is focused by one or two condenser lenses to a spot about 0.4 nm to 5 nm in diameter. The beam passes through pairs of scanning coils or pairs of deflector plates in the electron column, typically in the final lens, which deflect the beam in the x and y axes so that it scans in a raster fashion over a rectangular area of the sample surface.\n\nWhen the primary electron beam interacts with the sample, the electrons lose energy by repeated random scattering and absorption within a teardrop-shaped volume of the specimen known as the interaction volume, which extends from less than 100 nm to approximately 5 µm into the surface. The size of the interaction volume depends on the electron\'s landing energy, the atomic number of the specimen and the specimen\'s density. The energy exchange between the electron beam and the sample results in the reflection of high-energy electrons by elastic scattering, emission of secondary electrons by inelastic scattering and the emission of electromagnetic radiation, each of which can be detected by specialized detectors. The beam current absorbed by the specimen can also be detected and used to create images of the distribution of specimen current. Electronic amplifiers of various types are used to amplify the signals, which are displayed as variations in brightness on a computer monitor (or, for vintage models, on a cathode ray tube). Each pixel of computer video memory is synchronized with the position of the beam on the specimen in the microscope, and the resulting image is therefore a distribution map of the intensity of the signal being emitted from the scanned area of the specimen. In older microscopes images may be captured by photography from a high-resolution cathode ray tube, but in modern machines they are digitised and saved as digital images.\n\n</string>
    <string name="tecnica">\n<b>SAMPLE PREPARATION</b>\n\nSamples for SEM can be solid, bulk specimens of any size that will fit within the specimen chamber. Samples are generally mounted rigidly on a specimen holder called a specimen stub using a conductive adhesive, but mechanical clamping is a possible alternative. Several models of SEM can examine any part of a 6-inch (15 cm) semiconductor wafer, and some can tilt an object of that size to 45° and provide continuous 360° rotation.\n\nNonconductive specimens tend to charge when scanned by the electron beam, and especially in secondary electron imaging mode, this causes scanning faults and other image artifacts. For conventional imaging in the SEM, specimens must be electrically conductive, at least at the surface, and electrically grounded to prevent the accumulation of electrostatic charge. Metal objects require little special preparation for SEM except for cleaning and mounting on a specimen stub. Non-conducting materials are usually coated with an ultrathin coating of electrically conducting material, deposited on the sample either by low-vacuum sputter coating or by high-vacuum evaporation. Conductive materials in current use for specimen coating include gold, gold/palladium alloy, platinum, osmium, iridium, tungsten, chromium, and graphite. Coating with heavy metals may increase signal/noise ratio for samples of low atomic number (Z). The improvement arises because secondary electron emission for high-Z materials is enhanced.\n\nAn alternative to coating for some biological samples is to increase the bulk conductivity of the material by impregnation with osmium using variants of the OTO staining method (O-osmium tetroxide, T-thiocarbohydrazide, O-osmium).\n\n</string>
    <string name="coloreadas">Russet mite (Aceria anthocoptes)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas2">Yellow mite (Tribolium castaneum)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas3">Mould mite (Hypothenemus hampei)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas4">Grain itch mite (Pyemotes tritici)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas5">Peacock mite (Tuckerella)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas6">Parasitic wasp (Encyrtidae)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas7">Parasitoid wasp (Parasitica)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas8">Large red damselfly (Pyrrhosoma nymphula)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas9">Bed bug (Cimex lectularius)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas10">Red flour beetle (Tribolium castaneum)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas11">Coffee berry borer (Hypothenemus hampei)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas12">Silkworm (Bombyx mori)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas13">Mayfly (Baetis sp.)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas14">Great diving beetle larva (Dytiscus marginalis)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas15">Blow fly larva (Calliphora vomitoria)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas16">Yellow fever mosquito larva (Aedes aegypti)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas17">Yellow fever mosquito (Aedes aegypti)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas18">Moth (Heterocera)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas19">Butterfly proboscis (Lepidoptera)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas20">Cat flea (Ctenocephalides felis)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas21">Oriental cat flea (Xenopsylla cheopis)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas22">Dog flea (Ctenocephalides canis)</string>
    <string name="coloreadas23">Water bear (Tardigrada)</string>
    <string name="imagenes_sem">SEM Images</string>
    <string name="acerca"><b>UGLY BUGS</b>\n\nVersion 1.0\n\nJordi Guzmán Piferrer\n\nWEB: "http://jordiguzman.com/"\n\nEMAIL: jordiguz@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="dialogo_informacion_titulo">INFORMATION</string>
    <string name="dialogo_informacion" formatted="false">\nHere you will find technical information on how scanning electronic microscopes (SEM) work, their history and their uses.    \n\nYou\'ll also learn about the treatment of SEM\'s observed samples.\n\nThe texts in the three sections are taken from Wikipedia: \"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scanning_electron_microscope\".\n\nThere\'s also a selection of various types of SEM images.\n\n\n</string>
    <string name="problema_idioma">There is a problem with the language</string>
    <string name="servidor">There is a problem with the server</string>

</resources>